<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>blog.ashishapy.com</title>
   
   <link>https://blog.ashishapy.com/</link>
   <description>Amused at technology</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> Ashish Pandey</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Git (Source Code Management) - Strategy & Solution</title>
	  <link>//2016/09/git-source-code-management-system/</link>
	  <author>Ashish Pandey</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-09-16T10:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2016/09/git-source-code-management-system/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>It’s been long time, I haven’t posted anything on the blog. Though I have been engaged through meet ups with technical communities in Pune. It always excites me to explore new (which I never explored before) and go back to community and share my experience and knowledge.</p>

<p>This leads me and bring sense of responsibility, even when I am learning / exploring for myself. This has been a great advantage.</p>

<p>Recently I gave talk on <strong><a href="https://www.meetup.com/WebApp-Pune/events/231014541/">Git: SCM - Strategy &amp; Solution</a></strong> with <a href="https://www.meetup.com/WebApp-Pune/">WebApp-Pune meetup</a> event hosted at ThoughtWorks Pune. ThoughtWorks has always been generous to host such events, which has been catalyst for developer community to grow.</p>

<p>I have been using Git with Github/Bitbucket/GitLab for several years. But when I was asked by my colleagues including seniors/juniors about Git. I realised that power &amp; advantage of Git (or any other Source Code Management system) are not known / utilised by many. So I decided to give talk on “Git: SCM - Strategy &amp; Solution”.</p>

<p>Below is the slides from the talk.</p>

<p><strong>Slides:</strong></p>

<iframe src="//slides.com/ashishapy/git-scm/embed" width="576" height="420" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>It goes in detail about Git, Git commands, Git workflows, Collaboration, Branching strategy, Git in DevOps &amp; some bonus Github features.</p>

<p>Let me know your feedback or any question you have. Use comment section below or Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/ashishapy">@ashishapy</a>.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
